Gautham Yerroju

🛘 (702)-202-7794 | 🔀 gyerroju@gmail.com | 🏕 www.gauthamyerroju.com | 📮 GauthamYerroju | 🛅 Gautham-Yerroju

Overview

Full Stack Developer with around 8 years of experience in web development and Python. Master's in Computer Science. Quick to learn new tools, desire to use best practices and an eye for UI and UX.

Skills_

Web Development Express with Node.JS, Flask with Python, VueJS with Router and VueX, ReactJS, CSS3

Programming Python, JavaScript (ES.next), C++, C Databases MSSQL, Postgres, MongoDB

Frameworks and Libs VueJS, ReactJS, Mongoose, Express, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Odoo

VCS Git, Perforce

Experience

FleetCor Technologies, Inc.

California, U.S.A

FRONT-END DEVELOPER

Sep. 2020 - Present

- Worked with a global product team to develop an online credit card management system.
- · Owned components of a comprehensive in-house JavaScript front-end framework written using ES6 as a Progressive Web App.
- · Collaborated with design, back-end, API, network and QA teams on a daily basis to work on and deliver value in quick
- Followed the Scrum Agile process for collaboration and timely delivery of milestones.

Odoo Inc. California, U.S.A

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

Oct. 2018 - Jan. 2020

- Designed, developed and maintained custom business solutions for clients using open-source business software framework Odoo
- · Worked as part of cross-functional team of business advisors, clients and other developers
- · Attended weekly meetings with clients to solve technical roadblocks and serve as a subject matter expert
- Migrated data and code for multiple clients from legacy systems into newer versions of Odoo
- Participated in weekly code reviews, adhering to and promoting good coding standards
- · Independently managed projects in Kanban workflow, took ownership of modules and delivered quality solutions
- Gave a talk Odoo's External API at yearly company conference Odoo Connect
- Conducted week-long technical trainings on the Odoo framework every quarter to a multi-national cross-domain audience (including Toyota, Japan), generating a revenue of \$5,000 per attendee to the company
- Brought in an yearly revenue of over \$100,000 to the company through time billed, including monthly recurring revenue

University of Nevada, Reno

Nevada, U.S.A

RESEARCH ASSISTANT, ADVISED BY DR. FENG YAN

Aug. 2016 - Oct. 2018

- In collaboration with **NetApp, Inc.** Extreme scale storage failure analysis: a spatial-temporal approach
- Analyzed disk failures in real-world big data storage systems on a one-year data set
- Spatial and temporal characterization of various failure types
- Used conditional probability and Markov-chains to predict disk failures
- Test prediction algorithms on real data through simulations and analyze their accuracy

CA Technologies Telangana, India

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Dec. 2015 - Jul. 2016

- Designed and built a web application from ground up to publish quarterly surveys and aggregate results on a dashboard
- Solely responsible for requirements analysis, design, development, testing and deploying the project
- · Used ExpressJS with Node.js and Mongoose with MongoDB, with Active Directory for authentication and role management to integrate with existing infrastructure
- Role-based access control based on Active Directory roles
- · Used Material Design UI kit and subtle CSS3 animations to great effect to indicating multiple features like auto-saving, notifications and state transitions
- Learned all the required tools and implemented the application in a few months, following best practices (mostly from the 12-factor app paradigm)

FactSet Research Systems

Telangana, India

SENIOR ENGINEER

Jul. 2011 - Nov. 2015

• Developed and maintained a framework using IBM STAF and Python on which automated tests can be scheduled, their results stored and sent to test owners

- Integrated the framework with other internal tools using SOAP and REST APIs
- · Worked on developing a web application to schedule tests and view results (PHP, MSSQL and ¡Query)
- The developed test automation framework replaced most of the manual testing team's man-hours, freeing them to test for more elusive bugs and dramatically increase product coverage
- Was awarded the "Star Performer" yearly award three times
- Was consistently rated 'Exceeds Expectations' or 'Outstanding' in every half-yearly review
- Presented work-related topics to the team every two weeks in order to improve collective knowledge
- Interviewed and trained new hires for the team on required tools, technologies and workflows

Education

University of Nevada, Reno

Nevada, United States

MSc., COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Aug 2016 - Aug 2018

Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University Hyderabad

Telangana, India

BTECH., COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING

Mar 2007 - Apr 2011

Projects

Personal website and blog

GAUTHAMYERROJU.COM

- Hand-made CSS for home-page built to be responsive and performant
- Blogging workflow with GitHub pages and Prose.io

Slidey: CSS-only slider menu for websites

GAUTHAMYERROJU.COM/SLIDEY

- Simple and performant sliding menu for websites
- Case study on CSS3 features and BEM syntax

Open-source Keyboard Firmware

GITHUB.COM/GAUTHAMYERROJU/QMK_FIRMWARE

- Contributed fixes and feature enhancements to the QMK custom keyboard firmware
- Embedded programming in C, working within limitations of low memory and CPU
- · Contributed light-weight OLED animations and HID device features like rotary encoders and joysticks

VueJS web-app: Local Media Gallery

Server: NodeJS + SQLite

- · Scan folders for media on-demand
- · Auto-generate and cache thumbnails on-demand for images, animated GIFs and videos
- Use SQLite for persistent storage of scanned metadata

CLIENT: VUEJS + BULMA

- Single-file components with modular CSS and JS
- VueX to manage application state and Vue Router to reflect current state in URL
- Uses the Bulma CSS framework, custom performant CSS for effects and animations

Android app: Location Obfuscation

Android implementation of Location Obfuscation

- Implemented as an Android app "An Obfuscation-based Approach for Protecting Location Privacy" by Claudio et al.
- Location acquired by Google Places API, AOSP and Play Services location APIs with gracefully degrading location strategy
- The app generates an obfuscated location based on various techniques discussed in the research paper

Game Development

RUBY, RPG MAKER XP GAME ENGINE 🗗

Made several add-ons, scripts and systems for RPG Maker XP using the Ruby Game Scripting Engine.

Python, Custom game engine 🗹

Ship Showdown: A Python game example of a 2-player game, implemented using a custom game engine developed using Pyglet multimedia library.

JAVA, CUSTOM GAME ENGINE

Breakout-clone using Java Swing framework based on a custom game engine (a case study in game loop, resource management and graphics).

OPENGL, CUSTOM GAME ENGINE

SkyRoads clone using OpenGL and a custom level designer .

Open CV: Face counting in panning video

COMPUTER VISION

- Used Open CV to implement face counting in a panning video
- Used frame stitching followed by Haar cascades to detect and count faces

References

Manasa Kankipati

Enterprise Data Manager, Twitter mkankipati@twitter.com

Jigar Amin

Software Development Manager, Odoo Inc. jam@odoo.com

Dr. Feng Yan

Assistant Professor, University of Nevada, Reno fyan@unr.edu

Salman Kaleem

Enterprise Cloud Architect, Virtusa SalmanKaleemM@Virtusa.com